Neha Nautiyal

Email: nehahaha@gmail.com | Phone: 732-991-2517 | Philadelphia, PA 19119

LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/neha-nautiyal-09819880 | Github: https://github.com/NehaNautiyal/

Website: https://nehanautiyal.github.io

SUMMARY

Full-Stack web developer with certification from UPenn expected July 2019 passionate about learning new technologies. Enjoys tackling challenges with strong organization and collaborative skills. Effective communicator experienced in analyzing and solving problems logically. Brings experience with HTML/CSS, Javascript, jQuery, and more along with a love of learning developed through 8 years as a chemistry instructor. Eager to apply a varied skill set to make an impact within an organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Git, Bootstrap, Bash, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Firebase, Node.js

PROJECTS

Lost in Textlation | github.com/NehaNautiyal/Project-1 | nehanautiyal.github.io/Project-1 Back end Developer

This app uses Aylien and Merriam-Webster APIs to analyze the sentiment of user-inputted text, provide synonyms & antonyms to change tone of text, and update analysis.

- Worked with a team of 3 others using Git and Slack to plan, develop, test, and deploy app.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Firebase, Sentimood.js library, AYLIEN API, Merriam-Webster API.

Rock, Paper, Scissors - Multiplayer Game | http://github.io/RPS-Multiplayer | https://nehanautiyal.github.io/RPS-Multiplayer

Full-Stack Developer

This game used Firebase to allow 2 users to play Rock, Paper, Scissors. Chat function enabled.

- Planned, developed, tested, and deployed app.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, and Firebase.

GifTastic | http://github.com/NehaNautiyal/GifTastic | nehanautiyal.github.io/GifTastic/

Full-Stack Developer

This app allows users to search the Giphy API to generate 10 gifs about pre-populated elements, or an element of choice.

- Planned, developed, tested, and deployed app.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, and APIs.

Trivia Game | github.com/NehaNautiyal/TriviaGame | nehanautiyal.github.io/TriviaGame/

Front-end Developer

This app asks questions based on the user's chemistry knowledge.

- Planned, developed, tested, and deployed game.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, and jQuery.

RPG Game | github.com/NehaNautiyal/RPG-Game | nehanautiyal.github.io/RPG-Game/

Front-end Developer

This app uses atomic models to demonstrate onClick events.

- Planned, developed, tested, and deployed game.
- Uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, and jQuery

Word-Guess Game | github.com/NehaNautiyal/Word-Guess-Game | nehanautiyal.github.io/Word-Guess-Game/ Front-end Developer

This app is a hangman-style game in which users guess one letter at a time to complete the word.

- Planned, developed, tested, and deployed game.
- Uses HTML, CSS, and Javascript.

EXPERIENCE

<u>Upper School Science Teacher</u> – *Abington Friends School* – Jenkintown, PA

Aug 2016 - Present Teach all levels of chemistry (regular, honors, and AP) to high school students and all associated paperwork.

Key Accomplishments:

- Apply strong communication and interpersonal skills to work with students as well as colleagues.
- Act as a technology innovator using new devices in the classroom showing strong desire to learn.
- Seek feedback to improve showing openness to critique and desire to continually learn.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Science Department Coordinator – Olney Charter High School – Philadelphia, PA	Aug 2015 - June 2016
High School Chemistry Teacher - Olney Charter High School - Philadelphia, PA	Aug 2011 - June 2016

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadephia, PA – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certification, expected July 2019 University of Pennsylvania, Philadephia, PA – MS.E.D. in Secondary Education specializing in science, May 2011 University of Pennsylvania, Philadephia, PA – 1 year of doctorate in Chemistry, left program Aug 2008 Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ – B.A. in Chemistry, double minor in Physics & French, May 2007